theclymb.com 2019-12-26

# Privacy Policy | The Clymb

> Last updated: August 9, 2018 
> 
> The Clymb, a California corporation ("TCB") is committed to protecting the privacy of visitors to https://www.TheClymb.com (the "Site"). This notice describes our privacy policy (the "Privacy Policy") for the Site and all related websites, downloadable software, mobile applications (including tablet applications), and other services provided by us and on which a link to this Privacy Policy is displayed. This Privacy Policy does not apply to other websites to which we may link. You agree that by visiting the Site, you are accepting the privacy practices described in this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree with this Privacy Policy, you are not authorized to use this Site. 

## Secure Ordering:

Protecting your online order information on the Site is very important to us. In our shopping checkout process, we use Transport Layer Security (TLS), the industry-standard encryption technology that ensures the safety and security of your online order. When the letters "http" in the URL address change to "https," the "s" indicates you are in a secure area employing TLS. Making a credit card purchase is just as safe on our Site as it is by telephone. If you prefer to order merchandise from the website by phone, please call us toll-free [1 (877) 464-6936](tel:1-877-464-6936). For our customer service hours of operation visit Customer Care.

## Information We Collect:

#### Information You Provide Us –

In order to access this Site, you must first complete the registration process. During the registration process, we collect personal information such as your name and email address. Once you complete and submit your registration, you have automatically opted-in to receive email communications from us. If you no longer wish to receive these email communications, you may opt out by visiting https://www.TheClymb.com/MyAccount.aspx and selecting My Email. Alternatively, you may click the Unsubscribe link at the bottom of our marketing emails.

When you choose to use certain other features of the Site, such as making purchases, we collect personal information, such as your phone number, billing and shipping addresses and credit card information, and we may also request additional personal information, such as your shopping preferences and demographics.

If you choose to invite an individual to join the Site, you will need to provide his/her name and email address. The Clymb stores this information to confirm qualifying orders attributable to your account and to track the results of the invitation referrals.

#### Passively Collected Information –

In addition, we automatically gather certain information whenever you interact with the Site, such as the name of the domain from which you access the Internet, the date and time you access our Site, how frequently certain areas of the Site are visited, and the Internet address of the website from which you linked directly to our Site. Like many web sites, we employ the use of "cookies," web beacons, tokens, and other similar technology. Most browsers can be set to prevent cookies or to notify you when one is being placed. The Help feature on most browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable cookies altogether. However, cookies are necessary to utilize the Site. If you block or otherwise reject our cookies, you will not be able to add items to your Shopping Cart, proceed to Checkout, or access any portion of the Site that requires you to Sign in. We use the information we collect to measure the number of visitors to the different sections of our Site, their locations, search history, buying history and system performance to help us make our Site more useful to you. 

#### Mobile –

When you access the Site via a mobile device, we may receive information about your location and your mobile device, including a unique identifier for your device. We may use this information to provide you with location-based services, such as advertising, search results, and other personalized content. Most mobile devices allow you to turn off location services if you so desire. Most likely, such options are located in the device's settings menu. Your mobile service carrier or your device manufacturer should be able to assist you if you have any questions regarding how to turn off location services. 

## How We Use Your Information

We will not share or disclose your information to anyone except as described in this Privacy Policy. We use personally identifiable information in order to give you a more enjoyable and convenient shopping experience and to help us identify and/or provide information, products or services that may be of interest to you. We use your personally identifiable information to support and enhance your use of the Site and its features, including without limitation: fulfilling your order; providing customer service; tracking email invitations you send, and otherwise supporting your use of the Site. We may also track your past purchases to provide you with a personalized profile of your shopping history. In addition, we may notify you about new services or special promotional programs, or send you offers or information via email. 

We also use non-personally identifiable information in the aggregate, so that we can improve the Site and for business and administrative purposes. We may also use or share aggregated data that contains no personally identifiable information with third parties for any purpose.

## Who Do We Share Information With:

#### Affiliated Businesses

We work closely with affiliated businesses and in some cases, we operate stores, provide services, or sell product lines jointly with these businesses. You will be able to tell when a third party is involved in your transactions, and when we share customer information related to those transactions with that third party.

#### Third-Party Service Providers

We may employ other companies and individuals to perform functions on our behalf. Examples include fulfilling orders, delivering packages, sending postal mail and e-mail, removing repetitive information from customer lists, analyzing data, providing marketing assistance, providing search results and links, processing credit card payments, and providing customer service. In connection with their performance of services to maintain and operate the Site and specific features on the Site, certain trusted third parties may be permitted to access your information. They have access to personal information needed to perform their functions, but may not use it for other purposes. 

Notwithstanding any other provision, we partner with third parties that collect information across various channels, including offline and online, for purposes of delivering more relevant advertising to you. Our partners may place or recognize a cookie on your computer, device, or directly in our emails/communications, and we may share personal information with them if you have submitted such information to us, such as your name, postal address, email address, or device ID. Our partners may link the nonpersonal information we share with them to the cookie stored on your browser or device, and they may collect information such as your IP address, browser or operating system type and version, and demographic or inferred-interest information. Our partners use this information to recognize you across different channels and platforms over time for advertising, analytics, attribution, and reporting purposes. For example, our partners may deliver an ad to you in your web browser based on a purchase you made in a physical retail store, or they may send a personalized marketing email to you based on the fact that you visited a particular website. To learn more about interest-based advertising in general and to opt out, please visit <http://www.aboutads.info/choices>. To opt-out of the use of your mobile device ID for targeted advertising, please see <http://www.aboutads.info/appchoices>. 

#### Business Transfers

As we continue to grow, we might sell or buy companies, subsidiaries, or business units. In such transactions, customer information is generally one of the transferred business assets, but remains subject to the promises made in any pre-existing Privacy Policy (unless, of course, the customer consents otherwise). Also, in the event that LeftLane SportsTheClymb or substantially all of its assets are acquired by another entity, customer information will of course be one of the transferred assets. In such event, the transferee would be bound by the terms of this Privacy Policy. 

#### Protection of TheClymb and Others

We reserve the right to disclose account and other personal information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce or apply our Terms of Service and other agreements, or when we, in our sole discretion, believe it is necessary to protect the rights, property, or safety of LeftLane SportsTheClymb, our users, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction. Obviously this does not include selling, renting, sharing, or otherwise disclosing personally identifiable information from customers for commercial purposes in violation of the commitments set forth in this Privacy Policy. We also reserve the right to disclose information in order to comply with any subpoena, court order, administrative or governmental order, or any other requirement of law. 

#### With Your Consent

Other than as set out above, you will receive notice when information about you might be shared with third parties, and you will have an opportunity to choose not to share the information. Any personally identifiable information you elect to make publicly available on our Site (such as posting comments), will be available to others. If you remove information that you have made public on our Site, copies may remain viewable in cached and archived pages of our Site, or if other users have copied or saved that information. 

#### How Information is Stored and Processed

We are based in the United States and the information we collected is governed by U.S. law. By accessing or using our Site or otherwise providing information to us, you consent to the processing and transfer of information in and to the U.S. and other countries, where you may not have the same rights and protections as you do under local law. 

## How We Protect Your Information:

We are committed to protecting the information we receive from you, but we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to TheClymb or guarantee that your information may not be accessed, disclosed, altered or destroyed by breach of any of our industry standard physical, technical or managerial safeguards. We follow reasonable technical and management practices to help protect the confidentiality, security and integrity of data stored on our system. While no computer system is completely secure, we believe the measures we have implemented reduce the likelihood of security problems to a level appropriate to the type of data involved.

The Site encrypts your credit card number and other personal information using transport layer security (TLS) technology to provide for the secure transmission of the information from your device to our servers. In addition, only those employees and third parties who need access to your information in order to perform their duties are allowed such access.

It is also important for you to protect against unauthorized access to your computer and passwords. For example, be sure to log out when finished using a shared computer. 

## Accessing and Updating Your Personal Information and Preferences:

If you are a registered user, you may access and update your registration information and your preferences to receive email or other communications by visiting the My Account section of our site, or by sending an email to [membersupport@theclymb.com](mailto:membersupport@theclymb.com). Any user who receives an email invitation to join the Site may choose not to receive such invitations in the future by following the opt-out/unsubscribe instructions in the email invitations and, in addition, if you are a member, you can elect not to receive email from us by changing your preferences as indicated above. You may also update or change your personal information or preferences by sending email to [membersupport@theclymb.com](mailto:membersupport@theclymb.com). We will take commercially reasonable steps to implement your opt-out requests promptly, but you may still receive communications from us for up to ten business days as we process your request.

While we make efforts to accommodate requests to restrict our use of your information, we reserve the right to delete all or any portion of customer information if we are not able to reasonably accommodate a requested restriction.

## Children's Privacy and Parental Controls:

The Children's Online Privacy Protection Act imposes certain requirements on web sites directed at children under 13 that collect information on those children, and on web sites that knowingly collect information on children under 13. The Site is not directed at children under 13 and does not knowingly collect any personal information from children under 13.

## Data Security

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. We maintain appropriate administrative, technical and physical safeguards to protect personal data against accidental or unlawful destruction, accidental loss, unauthorized alteration, unauthorized disclosure or access, misuse, and any other unlawful form of processing of the personal data in our possession. This includes, for example, firewalls, password protection and other access and authentication controls. We use TLS technology to encrypt data during transmission through public internet. 

However, no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. We cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or store on the Site, and you do so at your own risk. We also cannot guarantee that such information may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach of any of our physical, technical, or managerial safeguards. If you believe your personal data has been compromised, please contact us at the email address below. 

If we learn of a security systems breach, we will inform you and the authorities of the occurrence of the breach in accordance with applicable law. 

## Data Retention:

We only retain the Personal Data collected from a user for as long as the user's account is active or otherwise for a limited period of time as long as we need it to fulfill the purposes for which we have initially collected it, unless otherwise required by law. We will retain and use information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. 

## Links to other sites

The Site may contain links to web sites operated by other third parties. TheClymb has no control over or responsibility for their content, information or activities, including security and use of personal information. We encourage you to read the privacy policies and terms of use of any third-party Site before submitting any personal information.

## Online account registration:

Registering with the Site will make your online shopping faster and easier. We can store your shipping addresses and billing information so that you don't have to enter them each time you shop. You will also be able to save your shopping basket, check your order status, and review your order history. Your registered information will be securely stored with us, and you can add, delete, or change your registered information at any time using your password.

## E-mails:

We may send promotional e-mails to you only if you have asked to receive them. Each time you receive an e-mail from us, you will be given the opportunity to "opt-out" or stop receiving them.

## Your California Privacy Rights

Please note that California law permits residents of California to request certain details about how their information is shared with third parties for direct marketing purposes. Under the law, a business must either provide this information or permit California residents to opt in to, or opt out of, this type of sharing. We qualify for this alternative option through the opt-out we provide above. California residents are subject to our California Privacy Policy Addendum. To access the California Privacy Policy Addendum, please Click Here

## Terms of Service and Privacy Policy Changes:

If you choose to visit the Site, your visit and any dispute over privacy is subject to this Notice and our Terms of Service, including limitations on damages, resolution of disputes and application of the law of the state of California. If we decide to change our Privacy Policy for the Site, we will post the revised Privacy Policy here so that you will always know what information we gather, how we might use that information and whether we may disclose it to anyone. Your continued use of the Site indicates your assent to the Privacy Policy as posted. We may e-mail periodic reminders of our notices and conditions, but you should check the Site frequently to see recent changes. Unless otherwise stated, our current Privacy Policy applies to all information that we have about you and your account.

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at:  
The Clymb  
P.O. Box 12959  
San Luis Obispo, CA 93406
